Guide to the Marjorie Greene Foster Papers, 1913-1930 (bulk 1913-1919
Department of Special Collections
Marjorie Greene Foster Papers,
1913-1930 (bulk 1913-1919
Special Collections M0516
Foster, Marjorie Greene, 1892-1919.
.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Gary F. Whiteley, 1989.
Biographical Note
Marjorie Greene Foster earned her bachelor's and master's degrees in Chemistry at Stanford, 1914 and 1915 respectively. While at Stanford she helped found Alchemia, the women's Chemistry honor society, and was elected to the Cap and Gown Society and Sigma Xi. She began her doctoral work at the University of California, Berkeley, in 1916, holding the George Williams Hooper Fellowship at the Hooper Foundation for Medical Research. She died in 1919 from influenza; her doctorate was awarded posthumously.
Scope and Content
These papers, dating largely from 1913 to 1919, concern Foster's academic career at Stanford and the University of California and include her master's thesis, reprint of an article, commencement programs, clippings, and photographs. Also included are letters of condolence to her father George H. Foster after her death, 1919, and notice of fellowship award in her honor, 1930.
Container List
- Chronology (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, postcard from Albrecht, T.S. to M. Foster, April 1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Diploma case (LSJU), program from dinner of the Chemistry Honor Society, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Castilleja School teaching contract, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Master's thesis, Studies on the Metallic Sulphides, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- LSJU commencement programs, 1914, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Newspaper clippings, c. 1914 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Reprint, The Effect of Adrenalin and Pituitrin on the Action of the Kidney under Strain, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- University of California, graduate school registration papers, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- University of California, Doctoral examination program, 1918-1919;University of California Fellowship Awards program, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1919,condolences upon her death (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Photographs of the Chemistry departments at Stanford and University of California (Box 1, Folder 12)